Finding Aid for A. Alfred Taubman College of Architecture and Urban Planning (University of Michigan) publications, 1876-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sub-Unit Publications
  - Architectural Research Laboratory
    - Sub-Unit Publications
      - Early Childhood Facilities
        - Reports
          - Some Sensible and Outrageous Ideas for the Future, 1972 (Box 7)
      - Environmental Design and Research
        - Bibliographies
          - Supplemental and Research Publications, 1969 (Box 7)
        - Reports
          - Environmental Design Research: A Faculty View, 1975 (Box 7)
      - Man Environment Reference
        - Abstracts
          - Environmental Abstracts, 1974 (Box 7)
      - School Environments Research Project
        - Abstracts
          - Environmental Abstracts, 1965 (Box 7)
        - Reports
          - Economic Planning for Better Schools: A Study of How to Use Available Resources to Best Advantage--Through Capital Budgeting--In Meeting the Changing Needs of Education by Benjamin Handler, 1960 (Box 7)
          - The Effect of Windowless Classrooms on Small School Children, July 1965 (Box 7)
          - The Effect of Windowless Classrooms on Elementary School Children, November 1965 (Box 7)
          - Environmental Analysis, 1965 (Box 7)
          - Environmental Evaluation, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Architecture and Planning Research Laboratory
    - Unit Publications
      - Brochures (Box 8)
        - Design America: The Founders' Council (Box 8)
        - Miscellaneous undated (Box 8)
      - Manuals
        - Laboratory Equipment Manual, version 1.0, 1985 (Box 8)
      - Monograph Series
        - Affiliative Behavior and the Physical Environment, by Rawia Fadel El Sadek, 1983 (Box 8)
      - Newsletters
        - The Competitive Edge, 1983-1987 (Box 8)
        - Funding Flash, 1990-1991 (Box 8)
        - Research News, 1984-1995, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Reports
        - The Architecture and Planning Research Laboratory (Draft), 1983 (Box 8)
        - Design and World Markets, 1986 (Box 8)
        - Energy Management and Retrofit--The Re:AAB Project (Final Report), [1983] (Box 8)
        - Integrated Approaches to Facilities Planning and Assessment: [Presented at] the Society for College and University Planning 21st Annual International Conference, by C.W. Clipson and R.E. Johnson, 1986 (Box 8)
        - Meeting Michigan's Housing Needs: The Role of Manufactured Housing, by Kate Warner, 1984 (Box 8)
        - Post-Professional and Doctoral Education in Architecture, 1991 (Box 8)
        - Simulating Future Worlds: A Review of Simulation Techniques for Research Planning and Design, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Sub-Unit Publications
      - Business and Design Education
        - Reports
          - First Things First 1986, 1988 (Box 8)
      - Design America
        - Reports
          - Design America: Promoting Design Excellence in America by Colin Clipson, 1989 (Box 8)
      - Factories for the Future
        - Brochures 1987 (Box 8)
      - The Role of Design in American Corporations
        - Reports
          - Business/Design Cases, 1984, 2 folders (Box 8)
          - Business/Design Cases (Slides), 1984 (Box 8)
          - Business/Design Indexes, 1984 (Box 8)
          - Business/Design Issues, 1984 (Box 8)
          - Business/Design Promotion, 1984 (Box 8)
          - Design and World Markets, 1986 (Box 8)
  - College of Architecture and Urban Planning Library Committee
    - Reports
      - The Current and Future State of the Art and Architecture Library: A Brief for Its Retention and Expansion in the Art and Architecture Building, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Daylighting Network of North America
    - Newsletters
      - DNNA News, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Department of Architecture Spring Course in Continuing Education
    - Computers and Performance Factors: Implications for Architecture
      - Manuals 1967 (Box 8)
    - Computers in Architecture
      - Brochures 1968 (Box 8)
  - John Dinkeloo Memorial Lecture
    - Lectures
      - Patkau Architects: Investigations into the Particular, 1995 (Box 8)
      - Richard Horden: Light Architecture, 1996 (Box 8)
      - Studio Granda, 1998 (Box 8)
  - Doctoral Program in Architecture
    - Brochures undated (Box 8)
    - Bulletins 1972-1991, undated, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Flyers
      - D. Arch. Students and Their Dissertations--Partial List, undated (Box 8)
    - Manuals
      - Administrative Policies and Procedures, 1990 (Box 8)
      - Faculty Handbook, 1989 (Box 8)
      - Qualifying Examination and Dissertation Procedures: (Interim Ph.D. Guidelines), 1991 (Box 8)
    - Syllabi
      - Core Seminar Syllabi, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Integrated Technology Instruction Center
    - Reports (Box 9)
      - Integrated Technology Instruction Center: Preliminary Investigations and Design Guide, Vol. 1-2, 1988, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Interior Design
    - Course Outline
      - The Historic Styles of Interior Design: Outline for D.D. 35 History of Interiors, 1936 (Box 9)
  - Master of Architecture Program
    - Reports
      - Heritage of a Landscape, 1995 (Box 9)
  - North Campus Studio
    - Proposals
      - North Campus: University of Michigan, Towards a Vital Community, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Office of Career Development
    - Directories
      - Resume Book, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Ph.D. in Architecture
    - Posters 1990 (Box 9)
  - Planning Accreditation Board
    - Reports
      - Planning Degree Initial Accreditation: Final Application and Appendices, 1987, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Planning and Policy Studies
    - Brochures undated (Box 9)
    - Bulletins
      - Graduate Programs in Planning and Policy Studies at Michigan, undated (Box 9)
  - Profession Exposure Program
    - Schematics
      - PEP2-WT75: A Schematic Housing Design Presentation for Off-Campus Housing Unit, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Solar Design Education Symposium
    - Design for the Sun
      - Poster 1978 (Box 9)
  - UM Programming Research Team
    - Reports
      - Architecture and Art Library Program, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Urban and Regional Planning Program
    - Unit Publications
      - Brochures 1967-2000, undated, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Flyers 1977, undated (Box 9)
      - Manuals
        - Urban Planning Orientation Handbook, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Sub-Unit Publications
      - Alumni Society
        - Newsletters
          - The U.P. Date, 1982 (Box 9)
          - Update, 1992 (Box 9)
      - Ph.D. Program in Urban and Regional Planning
        - Annual Reports
          - Annual Report, 1981 (Box 9)
        - Brochures undated (Box 9)
      - Ph.D Program in Urban, Technological, and Environmental Planning
        - Annual Reports
          - Annual Report, 1982 (Box 9)
        - Brochures undated (Box 9)
        - Programs
          - Symposium: "Applications of Planning Theory," April 1987 (Box 9)
        - Prospectus
          - The Integrative Corporate Planning Program (ICP) 1983 (Box 9)
  - Wallenberg (Raoul) Lecture
    - Brochures 1995, undated (Box 9)
    - Lectures
      - Architecture as a Humane Art, by Nikolaus Pevsner, 1972 (Box 9)
      - Architecture as a Humane Art by Eric Larrabee, 1973 (Box 9)
      - In Tribute to Raoul Wallenberg, by Sol King, 1995 (Box 9)
      - Traces of the Unborn, by Daniel Libeskind, 1995 (Box 9)
      - The Architecture of Community, by Vincent Scully, 1996 (Box 9)
      - Traffic in Democracy by Michael Sorkin, 1997 (Box 9)
      - Megaforms as Urban Landscape, by Kenneth Frampton, 1999 (Box 9)
    - Programs 1975-1985 (scattered) (Box 9)
  - Department of Urban Planning
    - Newsletters
      - "Planning Briefs," 1979 (Box 12)
  - Doctoral Program in Architecture
    - Dissertation Summaries 1989-2002 (Box 12)
  - National Policy Center on Housing and Living Arrangements for Older Americans
    - Newsletters
      - "Center News," 1980-1981 (Box 12)
  - Urban and Regional Planning Program (URP)
    - Unit Publications
      - Newsletters
        - "URP Post," April 1982 (see also "UTEP Post") (Box 12)
    - Sub-Unit Publications
      - Ph.D. Program in Urban, Technological, and Environmental Planning (UTEP)
        - Annual Reports
          - 1983-1984 (Box 12)
          - 1984-1985 (Box 12)
          - 1985-1986 (Box 12)
        - Newsletters
          - "UTEP Post," 1982-1985 (formerly "URP Post") (Box 12)
- Topical Publications
  - Alumni
    - Brochures 1996-2000 (Box 9)
    - Directories
      - Alumni Directory
        - 1956 (Box 9)
        - 1989 (Box 9)
      - Roster: The Association of Michigan Planners--Alumni of the University of Michigan in Professional Society, 1962-1964 (Box 9)
    - Exhibition Catalogs
      - Alumni Exhibition AD 50, 1956 (Box 9)
    - Alumni Reunion Weekend
      - Programs 1990-2005 (Box 9)
  - Art and Architecture Building
    - Architectural Drawings (Box 10)
      - College of Architecture and Design. New Art Center, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Brochures 1975 (Box 10)
    - Floor Plans undated (Box 10)
    - Programs 1975 (Box 10)
    - Proposals
      - The Architecture and Design Building: The U. of M. Project No. 85--Final Preliminary Design, 1970 (Box 10)
      - College Architecture and Design Project no. 85 by Swanson Associates, 1971 (Box 10)
      - Proposed New Building: College of Architecture and Design, U. of M., Ann Arbor, undated (Box 10)
    - Reports
      - The University of Michigan Architecture Building Report on Planning and Development, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Alumni Reunion Weekend
      - Programs 2010-2011, .ZIP file
  - Design Studios
    - Portfolios circa 1981, 1994, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Design Study Review
      - Schedules, 1995-198 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships
    - Posters 1985-1989, 1997-2004 (Box 10)
  - Foreign Study Programs
    - 1995 (Box 10)
  - Martin Luther King Day
    - Schedules 1996 (Box 10)
  - Semicentennial
    - Brochures
      - College of Architecture and Design, 1906-1956, 1956 includes Program from Semicentennial Exercises (Box 10)
  - Centennial
    - Brochures 2006 (Box 13)
    - “Century: A Second Century of Leadership,” 2003 (Box 13)
    - History
      - "TCAUP Centennial" -- pictorial history 2006 (Box 13)
    - Programs
      - Rewind/Pause/Fast Forward conference November 2006 (Box 13)
  - Charrettes
    - Booklets
      - "At Trumbull: Turning the Corner," 2000 (Box 13)
      - "Detroit Downtown, 2002" 2002 (Box 13)
      - "Detroit's Lower Cass: Corridor, Neighborhood, District?," 1999 (Box 13)
      - "Reflecting the Riverfront," 2003 (Box 13)
      - "Troy/Birmingham Transit Center: Briefing Book & Strategic Plan," 2008 (Box 13)
    - Flyers, 2000-2006 (scattered) (Box 13)
  - Design Studio
    - Abstracts
      - Architecture Thesis Studio 2002 (Box 13)
      - Thesis Final Reviews
        - 2005 (Box 13)
        - April 2006 (Box 13)
  - Environmental Consortium
    - Brochures
      - "An Urban Environmental Education Center in Ann Arbor," undated (Box 13)
  - Fellowships
    - Abstracts
      - Fellowships in Architecture, 2009 (Box 13)
    - Brochures
      - Leroy E. and Helen L. Kiefer Traveling Fellowship in Design undated (Box 13)
  - Michigan Solar House Project (MiSo)
    - Brochures 2005 (Box 13)
  - Mumbai Studios
    - Abstracts
      - Mapping Mumbai: University of Michigan Mumbai Studios Spring and Fall 2005 (Box 13)
  - Real Estate Forum
    - Brochures 1996 (Box 13)
- Student Publications
  - General Publications
    - Brochures
      - CBD 3+, undated (Box 10)
    - Class Composites undated (Box 10)
    - Journals
      - Architectural Discussions, 1978 (Box 10)
      - Dimension, 1956-1967, 7 folders (Box 10)
        (includes 1958 Dimension supplement entitled Current Student Work)
      - Dimensions, 1987-2000
        - Vol 2 #1-Vol. 8, 1987-1994, 12 folders (Box 10)
        - Vol. 9-14, 1995-2000, 3 folders (Box 11)
        - Vol. 15-Vol. 26, 2001-2013 (Box 13)
      - Rough Draft, 1995 (Box 11)
      - Student Publication, 1955, undated, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Manuals
      - The Template, undated (Box 11)
    - Newsletters
      - The Allnighter, 1973-1979, 5 folders (Box 11)
      - Architectural Synthesis, 1968-1969 (Box 11)
      - The Focal Point, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
      - Synergy, 1980-1983 Vol. 1-3 (Box 11)
      - This is Not Required Reading, 1987 (Box 11)
  - Specific Student Organization Publications
    - American Institute of Architecture Students
      - Programs
        - Studio Exhibition: An Exhibit of Work from the 1989 Fall Term Studios, 1989 (Box 11)
    - The Architectural Society
      - Yearbooks
        - The Architectural Yearbook of the U. of M., 1927 (Box 11)
    - Department of Urban Planning
      - Reports
        - Hubbard Richard--Detroit Riverfront: A Study Prepared by Graduate Students of the Department of Urban Planning, The U. of M., Under the Direction of Professor Gerald Crane, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Graduation Committee
      - Invitations 1980-1982 (Box 11)
      - Programs
        - Commencement Programs, 1980-2005 (scattered) (Box 11)
        - Commencement Programs, 2011-2012, .ZIP file
      - Yearbooks/Directories 1980-1997, 2000, 14 folders (Box 11)
    - The Radical Arky Gang
      - Newsletters
        - Free RAG, circa 1973 (Box 11)
- Taubman College of Architecture and Urban Planning Website
  The Taubman College Archived Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the Taubman College of Architecture and Urban Planning. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the College. The website series is arranged chronologically, with captures from 2002 and 2003 stored on CD. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Website capture May 15, 2002, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
  - Website capture May 22, 2003, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
  - Archived Taubman College of Architecture and Urban Planning home page 2010-[ongoing]
  - Archived websites related to the Taubman College of Architecture and Urban Planning 2010-[ongoing]